

#### Ray O'Neill

info@raymondoneill.ie
madebyray.com

www.linkedin.com/in/oneillray/
086 2328217

I am a user-centered Designer with over 6 years of combined agency, freelance and in-house experience. I have a huge passion for great user experiences and deep understanding of product design. I have a wide skillset which allows me to see any project from start to the end as well strong interpersonal skills to collaborate with clients and other stakeholders.

### **Relevant Experience**

## UX Designer - The Irish Times Ltd MAY 2015 - PRESENT

- Lead the design of key editorial projects such as <u>Election 2016</u>, AIB <u>Startup</u>
   Academy and <u>Project JOEY</u>
- Run design critiques, facilitate workshops, present to stakeholders and organise usability testing sessions.
- Carry out research directly with users on B2C and clients on B2B projects.
- Build and maintained UI style guides for various new and existing web & mobile applications by taking a data-informed approach to design.
- Practice iterative design using various prototyping tools to explore ideas quickly.
- Collaborate with team members, daily standups, weekly designer meetings and design studio sessions.
- Design iteratively using industry standard tools such as Principle, Sketch and Axure.

# Digital Designer - Struck & Spink (Melbourne) MAY 2014 - OCT 2014

- Led client training workshops and wrote documentation for clients' websites.
- Participated in client meetings and advised clients on current trends and best practices.
- Designed mobile first responsive websites
- · Improved team's development workflow by introducing SASS and better

- Wordpress theming practices.
- Maintained, designed & developed client websites using Adobe Creative Cloud, HTML, CSS, ¡Query & Wordpress.

## Digital Production Designer - Paddy Power OCT 2011 - DEC 2013

- · Helped with new brand rollout across business channels in 2013.
- Contributed to major website redesigns such as the live betting & affiliates websites.
- Designed and reworked marketing assets including landing pages, email headers, animated banners, flash banners.
- Wrote ActionScript code for expandable banners and video banners as well as standard flash banners for Google Double-Click.
- Assisted the Production Manager with controlling studio traffic, liaising with the marketing teams and the delegate to design team members.

#### **Education**

## MSc in User Experience Design - IADT 2016 - 2018 (EXPECTED)

- Entering year two year of part-time masters as while working full-time.
- · Writing my thesis on the subject of personalisation and mobile news.
- Succeeded in completing modules covering design thinking, prototyping, user research, usability, interaction design, psychology and visual Design.

#### Interaction Design (Erasmus) - Darmstadt, Germany

 Studied a range of digital media subjects such as digital culture, motion graphics and film, graphic design, interactive design and usability with a strong focus on web design and development as well and marketing and entrepreneurship.

## BA (Hons) in Multimedia - CIT 2007 - 2011

- · Received a 2.1 Honours Degree.
- Studied a range of digital media subjects such as digital culture, motion graphics and film, graphic design, interactive design and usability with a strong focus on web design and development as well and marketing and entrepreneurship.

#### **Toolset & Proficiencies**

- Sketch, Axure, Principle, Invision, Adobe Creative Suite, Lookback.io, Excel.
- Rapid prototyping, strategic thinking, workshop facilitation, user research methods, design thinking process, agile methodologies.

#### **Interests**

Rugby, live music, surfing, cycling, travelling, yoga